# ARBAB ASLAM

## **Electrical Electronics Engineer**

Contact: +92-332-6744909

Email: arbabaslam13@gmail.com



#### **SUMMARY:**

Electrical and electronics graduate with a focus on instrument and control system having about one year experience in generation and control system now interested to sharpen career as an electrical and instrument engineer. Previous job and internship experience of power sector has an indepth knowledge of electrical system and safety standards.

### PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Organization: Best Fibres Pvt Ltd

(Textile Company)

**Tenure:** August 2017 – Jan 2018 **Designation:** Electrical Engineer

B

### **RESPONSIBILITIES:**

- Controlled and supervised generators, and auxiliary equipment in power generating plants.
- Testing and calibrating voltage, phase angle, amperes and circuits using voltmeter and ohmmeter.
- Maintenance and service cooling tower and R/O plant with supervision and guidance.
- Supervision of all DB, Breaker, Panels and Circuit wiring and testing.
- Utilized circuit layouts to solder circuit boards for later assembly.

#### TRAININGS & WORKSHOPS

- Programmable Logic Controller from JPI.
- Attended CPD's during the session of Engineering.
- Attended workshop on Process design and simulation by PEB held at University.

#### **INTERNSHIPS:**

Organization Name	Duration	Date	Certificate
WAPDA Engineering Academy, Faisalabad, Pakistan	One Month	July 2016-Aug 2016	Yes
500KV Grid Station NTDC, Gatti, Faisalabad, Pakistan	One Month	May 2016- Jun 2016	Yes

## **BS FINAL YEAR PROJECT:**

<b>Project Title</b>	UAV Quad-copter using adaptive controller and low cost sensors		
Brief Description	<ul> <li>Ability to sustain at a height of 250 feet, with a feature of auto-balance and auto-land.</li> <li>Awarded highest marks among the batch by the evaluating committee</li> <li>Detailed research in the fields of Control system, VLSI and Electric Circuits</li> </ul>		

## **ACADEMIC EDUCATION:**

Year of Completion	Degree/ Certificate	Marks %	Institute/Board Name
2017	B.Sc. Electrical Engineering Specialization in Electronics	(74.16%)	The University of Faisalabad, Pakistan
2012	Intermediate (Pre-Engineering)	(65.9%)	B.I.S.E, Faisalabad, Pakistan
2009	High School (Science)	(84.4%)	B.I. S.E, Faisalabad, Pakistan

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

- Matlab and Simulink Modeling
- MikroC Programming
- C++ Programming
- Microwind and Modelsim for Electronic Devices
- Programming of PIC /Microcontrollers
- Electric Circuit Designing using Proteus
- PCB designing using Proteus

## **MEMBERSHIP:**

Member of 'Pakistan Engineering Council (PEC)' as a Registered Engineer (ELECT 66004)

## PERSONAL INFORMATION:

_ •	
Father Name	Muhammad Aslam
Date Of Birth	13 Oct, 1993
CNIC#	33301-5687701-7
Address	House#60-B, Chenab Gardens, Samundari Road, Faisalabad

Supporting Documents and References will be provided on request.